Guide to the China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Papers of Individuals: A - G, Series I
  - Fagg, John Gerardus and Margaret Gillespie Fagg
    - Photographs: 11 of Chinese individuals in ceremonial dress (pre-1911), multiple image photo of John Fagg, photo of his church, 1913, no date (Box 372, Folder 11-12)
  - Falck, Elizabeth H.
    Biog. info: ACM Shanghai (L.1923-L.1929)
    - Photographs re. various Chinese hospitals and patients, 1920-1938 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material: Chinese language hymnal, 1932-1941 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Farrior, S. C.
    Biog. info: PN Hangchow, Shanghai, Chinkiang
    - Correspondence: Circular letter, 1939-1944 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Typescript writings incl. "One hundred hungry children", etc., 1939-1941 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Faurot, Albert
    ABCFM, Foochow; music teacher at Hwa Nan College
    - 4 circular letters, including re. "liberation" of Ingtai, Fukien, 1947-1950 (Box 376, Folder 19)
  - Fast, Aganetha
    Biog. info: MGC Kaichow (1918-1949)
    - Correspondence: Letters and photographs, 1940-1962 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Fenn, Courtenay Hughes*
    Biog. info: PN Peking
    - Bound scrapbook re. the siege of Peking 1900 during the Boxer Rebellion, with enclosures (Box 68, Folder 1-3)
    - Copy of scrapbook, "The siege of Peking" (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Photographs and (negatives): The Peking Presbyterian Church, 2nd Petaiho Conference, 1899, etc. (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Typescript Diary of Courtenay Hughes Fenn, 1866-1927 (Box 69, Folder 2-4)
      Digital copy available in Divinity Library AdHoc Digital Image and Text Database.
    - Fenn's Chinese-English Pocket Dictionary - Revised American Edition, published by Harvard University Press, 1944 (Box 376, Folder 12)
  - Fenn, William F.
    - Typescript ms.: Beginning of "A History of the University of Nanking" (Box 315, Folder 13)
  - Ferguson, John C.
    Biog. info: MEFB Shanghai 1887-?
    - Published mat.: Family history (1830-1877) by Mary Ferguson, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Fisher, Alzo John
    Biog. info: PN Canton (1902-1947)
    - Correspondence: Letter to friends from Alzo John Fisher, 1940 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Forster, Ernest H. and Clarissa*
    Biog. info: ACM Yangchow, Nanking, Kiangsu Province; Ernest Forster had served in China for seventeen years before returning to Boston to marry Clarissa Townsend in 1936. Shortly after their return to Yangchow, Japanese hostilities forced their removal to Nanking. Ernest stayed in Nanking throughout the Japanese occupation while Clarissa was evacuated to Shanghai.
    - Materials from disbound scrapbook - letters, clippings, ephemera, incl. re. Nanking Massacre (Box 263, Folder 1-9)
    - Photo albums: China and Shanghai, 1927-1939 (Box 264, Folder 1-2)
    - Photographs: Photo albums, Nanking, Yangchow, ACM work in Japan, 1935-1938 (Box 265, Folder 1-4)
  - Forsythe, Irene
    American Presbyterian, Tsingtao
    - 2 circular letters, 1950 (Box 376, Folder 20)
  - Forth, Lydia Mildred
    Biog. info: (1868-1894) Served under China Inland Mission in North China for 7 1/2 years.
    - Bound album "China Missionary 1887-1897" includes photographs of CIM missionaries and Chinese colleagues, notes, missionary ephemera, 1882-1894, n.d. (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Frame, Alice Seymour Browne (Mrs. Murray Scott)
    Biog. info: ABCFM Yenching Univ. (L. 1916-L.1940)
    - Correspondence: Letters to friends and family, 1936-1938 (Box 70, Folder 6-12)
  - Fulton, Robert and Anne Edwards Fulton
    Biog. info: YM (1933-35, 1944-46) Yenching Univ. (1939-1941) Huachung Univ. (1947-1950); (see also: Dwight Edwards Papers, RG 12)
    - Midwest China Oral History and Archives Project Transcript, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 4-5)
  - Funk, Grace A. (Mrs. H. Edwin V. Andrews)
    Biog. info: ABCFM Shaowu (1907-1925)
    - Letters (excerpts) published, clippings pasted in cash account book, 1911-1925 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings pasted into notebook, 1906-1911 (Box 357, Folder 5)
  - Galt, Curtis M., M.D. and Mabel Moore Galt
    Biog. info: PN Kinlung Kiang, Yunnan (L.1924-L.1936)
    - Biography of Mabel Moore Galt by CMG (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Galt, Elmer
    ABCFM, North China
    - 2 circular letters, 1948, 1950 (Box 376, Folder 21)
  - Galt, Howard S.*
    Biog. info: ABCFM Tungchow, Peking (1899-1943)
    - Handwritten ms: "Internment camp at Wei Hsien, Shantung - Mar-Sep 1943", "Journey of repatriots, Wei Hsien to New York - Sep-Dec 1943", 1946 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Memoirs of Ralph Galt, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 1a)
  - Gamble, Sidney D.*
    Biog. info: YMCA Peking (1918-1932)
    - Bound book of mimeographed letters, 1924-1927 (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - Gamewell, Mary Porter*
    Biog. info: WFMS Peking (1871- )
    - Handwritten "History of the Peking Station of the North China Mission of the Women's Foreign Missionary Society of the Methodist Episcopal Church", with photographs and other printed documents pasted in. (Selected photographs available in IMPA: http://www.usc.edu/isd/archives/arc/digarchives/mission/), c.1899-1926 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Garrett, Frank and Garrett, Verna Waugh
    Biog. info: UCMS Nanking, Nantung Nanking Theol. Sem. (1896-1932)
    - Dairy (fragments) 31 Oct-Nov 1914 Verna Waugh Garrett; 13-17 Aug 1937 Frank Garrett (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letter to Frank Garrett from McNally Shanghai; Letter from FG to Gilbert, US Vice Counsul, Nanking, 1909, 1911 (Box 74, Folder 2-3)
    - Corres: Letter from Verna Waugh Garrett to friends, Nanking, Nantungchow, 1915, 1916, 1918 (Box 74, Folder 4-5)
    - Corres: Letters from Mardie (Margaret Garrett Smythe) and B.A. Abbott (Editor, The Christian Evangelist); A. J. Bowen, W. Ellackling, Dorothy Macklin; Letter to friends, 1928-1939 (Box 74, Folder 6-9)
    - Newsletters, 1939, 1950 (Box 74, Folder 10-13)
    - Corres: Letters incl. from James Henry McCallum, Nanking; Wei Chi Yu; to Mardie (Margaret Garrett Smythe) from Luke (Luther Shao), 1946, 1948, 1950 (Box 74, Folder 14-18)
    - Typescript essay: "Nantungchow" by Verna Waugh Garrett, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Typescript Articles by FG: "What is Wrong with our Position", "Disciple Government", "Among China's Farmers", "Hindering the Missionary", "Our China Mission and China's Poverty", "Evangelising in China"., 1928, 1932 (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - Typescript Report by FG re. the Hankow Conference and the work of the Evangelistic Association, 1910 (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - Handwritten notes on "China-Japan War" by FG to which is attached p. 719 of The Christian Century, 8 June 1938 and an AP clipping (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Typescript mat: Excerpts from The Missionary Intelligencer 1896-1900; Central China Christian 1901 re. Dr. Frank Garrett, 1896-1901 (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - Printed mat: Excerpts from China Weekly Review, World Call, 1919-1932 (Box 74, Folder 24-25)
    - Typescript poems; Newspaper clippings concerning Nantungchow and the Garretts, 1924-1926 (Box 74, Folder 26-28)
    - Newspaper clippings concerning evacuation of missionaries, Shanghai Times; concerning R.W. Garrett, J.H. Garrison and James Ware, 1927 (Box 74, Folder 29-30)
    - Letter of support for Famine Colonization Assoc., (Chinese), with translation and Miss Lyon's birthday songs (Chinese) (Box 74, Folder 31)
    - Final examination, Department of Missionary Training, University of Nanking by Mrs. Frank (Verna Waugh ) Garrett, 1916 (Box 74, Folder 32)
    - Obituary of Frank Garrett; Program, Service of Christmas music, 1949, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 33)
    - Photographs: Frank and Verna Garrett, missionary colleagues, Chinese colleagues and students, primarily in Nantungchow, 1916-1930, n.d. (Box 74A, Folder 1)
    - Photographs: Scenes of Chinese life, mission work, primarily in Nantungchow and vicinity, 1917,1930, n.d. (Box 74A, Folder 2)
    - Photographs: Missionaries, Chinese colleagues and students, primarily in Nanking, 1908-1923, n.d. (Box 74A, Folder 3)
    - Photographs: Scenes, primarily in Nanking, incl. University of Nanking, 1929, 1936, n.d. (Box 74A, Folder 4)
    - Photographs: Missionaries and scenes in Kuling, 1904-1931, n.d. (Box 74A, Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Taken in and around Shanghai at time of Japanese invasion, 1937 (Box 74A, Folder 6)
    - Photographs: UCMS missionary groups, 1922, 1962, n.d. (Box 74A, Folder 7)
    - Photographs: miscellaneous scenes, including "Album of Tsingtao", n.d. (Box 74A, Folder 8-9)
  - Garvie, Margaret
    From 1945 to 1951 Garvie was on the staff of the Student Movement of the National YWCA in China. During this time period Garvie was collecting documentation related to left-wing movements in the YMCA/YWCA and Chinese Student Movement.
    - Photocopies of typescript and published documents in English, including "Where the Wind Blows in Peiping?" by Kiang Wen-Han, "Christian Churches in Communist China" by T. C. Chao, "Revolution in China" by T. C. Chao, National Christian Council of China "NCC News" and meeting records, "Christian Emergency Council", "Hangchow 1947 - Impressions of World's YWCA Council meeting", 1947-1950, no date (Box 373, Folder 2)
    - Photocopies of typescript and published documents in Chinese, 1947-1950, no date (Box 373, Folder 3-4)
  - Giffin, Raymond H. and Giffin, Jean
    Biog. info: Foochow (1947-1949)
    - Typescript letters and reports, 1948-1964 (Box 75, Folder 1-3)
    - Mimeographed circular letters from missionaries who remained in China 1950-1951, incl. Matthews, Dutton, Faurot, Helen Smith, Dewar, White, Fairfield. Circular letters from Mid-Fukien Synod of the Church of Christ in China and American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions re. church in China after Communist takeover (Box 339, Folder 4)
  - Gleysteen, W. H.
    American Presbyterian, Peking
    - Typescript report on effect of floods in north China and flood relief efforts, 1918 (Box 376, Folder 22)
  - Goddard, Dean
    Biog. info: ABFMS Ningpo (1870-1903)
    - Photographs: Goddards, etc., 1895-1896, 1902, 1918-1925 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Corres: Letter to his son, 1902 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Printed mat: Chinese language material, calendar, pam. (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Memorabilia - Chinese and English language (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Writings and clippings re. Dean William, 1875, 1876 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Exhibition Devices incl. note papers (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Typescript report re. Wm. Dean: "Class of '1876' U of R, 1906 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Collected mat: Buddhist Sacred Book (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Domestic Ledger of William Dean (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Photographs: Peoples and scenes (Box 81, Folder 1-2)
    - King Chulalongkom's letter, 1890 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Plate from photo of grave of Josiah (1813-1854) and of Eliza, wife of JRG (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Plate from photo of King Chulalongkom taken by Geo. H. Hastings in Boston 147 Tremont St. Corner West St. (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Plate from photo of graves of JRG and Fanny Dean in Ningpo Cemetery (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Artifacts - doll, fan, spoon and book-ends (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Wallet/small purse (2nos.) (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Artifacts (Box 83)
    - Collected material: Japanese newspaper, 1895 May 17; Receipts from Buddhist Temple; Buddhist Nunnery believer's distribution (Box OVd5)
  - Gold, Ralph G.
    Biog. info: YMCA Foochow (1911-1927)
    - Photographs: Peoples and scenes, etc (Selected photographs available in IMPA: http://www.usc.edu/isd/archives/arc/digarchives/mission/) (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1912-1920, 1927-1928 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Printed material: Chinese language material (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Printed material: "Descriptive and Historical Sketch of Port Arthur", "Christianity and national Progress", "The Minneapolis Journal", etc., 1910-1927 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Printed material: "Journal of the China Branch of the Royal Asiatic Society", 1887 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Private Law College, Fukien (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Photographs (Box 85, Folder 1-10)
    - Photographs: Album, ca. 1911-1913 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Photographs - misc., 1912, 1914 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Photographs - YMCA, YWCA Activities Personnel, 1911-1914, 1923 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Photographs - YMCA Activities incl. anti-cholera Campaign (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Photographs for exhibit; poster of depicting events in Chinese history, No date (Box OV1)
      Photographs of uncertain origin - possibly Gold
  - Goodrich, Chauncey Goodrich and Sarah Boardman Clapp Goodrich
    Biog. info: ABCFM Peking, Tungchow (1865-1925) ABCFM Kalgan, Peking (1879-1923)
    - Photographs: "Peoples and buildings" incl. Union Theological College, 1909-1910 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Photographs: "Peoples and scenes" (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Photographs: four mounted sets incl. Congregational Church, Peking, Ladies house ABCFM Compound, Bridgman Academy, etc., 1905-1916 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Goodrich to family, 1868, 1891-1894 (Box 87, Folder 4-7)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Goodrich to Prudential Committee, Godson Smith, 1894 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Goodrich to family, 1895-1923 (Box 87, Folder 9-13)
    - Correspondence: Letters to Chauncey Goodrich, 1892-1894 (Box 87, Folder 14-18)
    - Typescript material: Biographical material written by Dorothea Smith Coryell (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - Printed material incl. "A Bible Study on the Coming of Jesus" by CG, etc., 1910 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Sarah Goodrich primarily to her family, 1884-1913 (Box 88, Folder 1-88)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Sarah Goodrich primarily to her family, 1913-1923 (Box 89, Folder 1-42)
    - Journal (fragments) of SBG, Peking, 1913-1921 (Box 89, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence, telegrams concerning legal proceedings from Wang Chung-hui, Evelyn Dewey, Alice Huey, SBG, Leonard, Peking, 1918-1920 (Box 89, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence: Letters to Sarah Boardman Goodrich, 1892-1923 (Box 89, Folder 45-48)
    - Correspondence: Others letters, 1892, 1894, 1913, 1919, 1921, 1925, 1926 (Box 89, Folder 49)
    - Collected Material, incl. photo of fan signed by missionaries during siege of Peking during the Boxer Rebellion (Box 90, Folder 1-2)
    - Journal by SBG, 1900 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Letter to Mr. Swanson from Rowland M.Cross incl. memorial service concerning SBG, 1955 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Biographical material on SBG (1855-1923) (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Typescript Articles by SBG: "The Relationship of Foreign Children to the Chinese", "The Hoopoe Old Lady", "Mary E. Andrews, the Women Board's First Gift to China", "Children's Rights","The human Plant", "The Peking Woman's Paper and its Editor, Mrs. Chang", "The Mothers of China", "Young Woman's Societies of the World's Woman Christian Association", "Miss May Chapin", "What is the WCTU doing in China?", "Memoranda regarding Help for China", "Congregationalism, Some of the Reasons why it Commands our Unswerving Loyalty and Devotion", etc., 1897, 1909 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Typescript Report by SBG: "Reports and related documents of Committee on Shelters for Jinriksha Men", 1917-1920 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Typescript Report by SBG: "Kung Li Hui Refugee Camp", "Extra Mission Activities", etc., 1920 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Handwritten Class notes: "Milton's Paradise Lost", "Religious Education, Christian Womanhood and Home" and Lessons in Scriptures (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Reports: Financial reports and receipts, 1922 (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material: Program, Christmas entertainment, Report of the Peking Association for the Relief of Destitute Native Women, Report of the Home for Old Men and Aged Couples, Children's Twentieth Century Offering, 1922-1923 (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - Documents (Chinese): Letter to SBG from Peking Police, Suggestions for Christian Westernization of China, Calling cards, General Wu, Wang (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Documents (Chinese): WCTU Charter, Sample of Temperance Pledge, List of Students, class role, List of donors, Jinricksha Fund (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Transcription (Chinese): Genesis I-X, Passages from John, Paul, summaries of John Milton's Paradise Lost. (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1912, 1918-1920 (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Misc: Guest list, Missionary party, 1913 (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - Self-published books by Dorothea Smith Coryell re. the Goodrich family, "China Women" and "Love's Call to China", 1984, n.d. (Box 351, Folder 6-7)
    - Photos (Box OV4)
  - Goodrich, Luther Carrington and Anne Swann Goodrich
    Biog. info: Luther, son of Chauncey and Sarah Goodrich, worked for the China Medical Board of the Rockefeller Foundation 1920-1925, professor at Columbia University; visiting professor in Peking 1937; Anne went to China in 1920 serving under ABCFM
    - Circular letters, 1946-1951 (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Photographs: individual and group portraits of Chinese people and missionaries, including apparent famine victims in ragged clothing, ca. 1920-1924 (Box 377, Folder 2)
    - Photographs: scenes from Chinese life, including street scenes, opium den, ca. 1920-1924 (Box 377, Folder 3)
    - Photographs: buildings and scenes, including Ming Tombs and Peitaho ((Beidaihe) resort, ca. 1920-1924 (Box 377, Folder 4)
    - Photographs: pages from photo album: individuals and scenes in China, ca. 1920-1924 (Box 377, Folder 5)
  - Goodsell, Fred Field
    Biog. info: ABCFM executive; see also the David Stowe Papers, RG 156
    - Typewritten ms: "The American Board in China 1830-1950 Review and Appraisal. Appendix II: Personnel of the China Missions" (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Graham, Helen Campbell
    Biog. info: Served on faculty of North China American School 1931-1934
    - Photo album and loose photos, incl. scenes of Tungchow, Lu Ho, Peking, Great Wall, Tai Shan, Ming Tombs (Box 366, Folder 1-2)
  - Grandi, Elsa Sjoberg
    Swedish missionary stationed in Mongolia and Szechuan, 1947-199
    - Photograph album documenting journey from Sweden to China and Mongolia, Communist invasion, return home, 1947-1951 (Box 373, Folder 5)
    - Biographical documentation: passport, photographs, newspaper articles
  - Graves, Lucy J.
    Biog. info: ACM Shanghai St. John's Univ. (L.1916-L.1940)
    - Manuscripts and Memorabilia incl. photos of Bishop Graves, a conference of clergy, Kiangsu Diocesan Convention, etc., 1880s, 1930s (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Gray, G. F. S.
    Biog. info: Anglican: CMS, SPG Guilin, Nanjing, Beijing, Wuchang
    - Typescript manuscript of history of Anglican mission work in China: "Anglicans in China: A History of the Chung Hua Sheng Kung Huei" 257 pp. plus indices (Box 151, Folder 1-5)
  - Grayson, Dorothy D. Brewster*
    Biog. info: MEFB Foochow, Kutien (1933-1949) (formerly Mrs. Harold N. Brewster)
    - Typescript memoir: "We Immigrants were Welcome" re. missionary life in Kutien and Foochow, 1933-1944, 1947-1949 (Box 91, Folder 14-15)
  - Greene, Theodore Chase and Phoebe Cutler Greene
    Biog. info: Went to China in 1926 under Board of Foreign Missions of Presbyterian Church. TCG was medical doctor on staff of Douw Hospital in Peking 1926 to 1934. In 1935 he jointed the faculty of Cheeloo Medical School in Tsinan, Shantung. The Greenes returned to the U.S. in 1950.
    - "A Medical Mission in China: Douw Hospital and its Work 1926-1931": volume of text and photos compiled by TCG, documenting the work of the hospital, edited and bound by their daughter Joan Swift Greene Smith, 1989 (Box 351, Folder 8)
    - "An American Boy in China: Ralph Cutler Greene 1928-1941": volume compiled by TCG following death of eldest son from encephalitis in Jenshow 1941 consisting of letters written by TCG to his father, Dr. Philip Smead Bird and other materials (Box 351, Folder 9)
  - Grierson, Robert
    Biog. info: CIM Chekiang Province Pingyang, Wenchow (1885-L.1911)
    - Photographs from Shanghai, Wenchow - scenes and individuals, c.1898-1900 (Box 257, Folder 1)
    - Diary (Box 257, Folder 2)
    - Photograph album: includes photos of Grierson and his work in China as well as photos of the Middle East and Caracas, Venezuela, ca. 1900 (Box 377, Folder 1)
  - Griffin, Pansy P.
    Biog. info: WFMS Changli, Peking (L.1921-L.1940)
    - Photographs: people, 1940-1950 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Pansy P. Griffin to Mel, 1921-1926 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Letters from PPG to family and friends, 1931-1939 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1947, 1950, 1959 (Box 91, Folder 6-7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1937, 1950 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Groff, Anne M.
    Biog. info: ACM Shanghai, Chengtu (L.1921-L.1936)
    - Scrapbook Contents: Commentary, photographs, correspondence, 1921-1927, 1932 (Box 91, Folder 9-10)
    - Scrapbook Contents: Commentary, photographs, clippings, material re. Burma road journey, 1941 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook Contents: Commentary, photographs, correspondence, collected mat. incl. re. Gripsholm, 1942-1943 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Scrapbook Contents: Commentary, photographs, correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - Gu, Chang-sheng
    Biog. info: SDA Shanghai (b. 1919)
    - Memoir in Chinese (Box 244, Folder 1)
    - Typescript Papers given while research fellow at Yale: "A Brief Account of my Research Works", "The Study of Religons in China Today", "A Retrospect on Religious Policy and Practice in Socialist China (1949-1984), 1985-1986 (Box 244, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper article: "Chinese Professor will not go Home Again" - Cape Cod Times, 1989 (Box 244, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 249, Folder 1-5)
    - Additional papers documenting stay in US, 1984-1986 (Box 249, Folder 6)
    - Typescript paper read at meeting of American Society of Missiology: "Christianity in China Today"; Chinese language articles, including "Yale-in-China Association and the Sino-U.S. Cultural Exchange", "John Fryer 1839-1928 - The Pioneer of Spread of Knowledge of Science in Modern China", 1985-1992 (Box 249, Folder 7)
  - Gundlach, Adelaide
    Biog. info.: Gundlach (1890-1987) was born in Rochester, NY, daughter of a minister in the German Reformed Church. Following attendance at a business college and involvement with the YWCA, she entered Oberlin College in 1914. She went to Ginling College, Nanking, in 1918 and worked as Secretary of the college for four years before returning to the U.S. From 1923-1955 she served as Registrar, with expanded responsibilities, at Berea College in Kentucky.
    - Letters to family members in the U.S. documenting Gundlach's life and work at Ginling College, 1919 Jan-1921 Dec, n.d. (Box 350, Folder 1-8)
      Folder 7 contains a CD with scanned versions of the letters as well as the photographs found in folders 14-16.
    - Material related to Ginling College, including booklets, map, newsletter, history, 1920-1975 (Box 350, Folder 9-10)
    - Biographical information, 1962-1987 (Box 350, Folder 11)
    - Personal diary, 1921 (Box 350, Folder 12)
    - Collected material: leaflet re. a Movement Toward a Christian International; memorial booklet re. Lydia Brown Hipps, 1920, 1924 (Box 350, Folder 13)
    - Photographs, primarily of Chinese people and scenery, ca. 1920 (Box 350, Folder 14-16)
    - Painted scroll, no date (Box OV3)
- Papers of Individuals: H - M, Series II
  - Hafner, Victor R.
    Biog. info: LC-MS Hankow, Taiwan, Hong Kong
    - Correspondence: Biographical information, 1959, 1979 (Box 246, Folder 1)
    - Typed and handwritten ms. in English and Chinese by VRH: "The Limits of Academic Freedom in Relation to the Commitment to the Church's Confessions, A Lofty View of Inspiration, etc...", 1971 (Box 246, Folder 2)